

ERIC DACAL SANCHEZ

Video Game Programmer and Artist

Contact info



eric@dacal.es



(+34) 691502055

Socials

in Linkedin



Portfolio website

https://eric-dacal.vercel.app/

Languages

- Spanish
 Native
- CatalanNative
- English
 Level B2

Skills

Programming



Art



About

As a **Computer Engineer** with 5 years of professional experience in the industry, I am not only driven by the intricate mechanisms of technology but also by the art that lies within it.

Passion fuels every project I undertake, whether it's crafting efficient algorithms or indulging in the art of visual design. Throughout my academic and personal ventures, I have continuously honed my **artistic** abilities, finding joy in intertwining the realms of technology and art.

My insatiable curiosity and eagerness to learn ensure that I am always ready to embrace new challenges and innovative solutions.

Education

2022-2023



UPC School

Master's Degree in Advanced Programming for AAA video games

2014-2019





Experience



Horizon Games

Art Lead and Programmer | 2022 - 2023

Student project, in which we developed a graphics engine from scratch using C++ as a class, and created a game with it. Students took on various roles within the development team. In my case, I was the Art Lead and also served as a programmer.

MCA

MCA Spain / Ficosa Electronics SL

Full Stack Enginner | 2022 - Current

Working as external in Ficosa Electronics SL as full stack engineer.



Justinmind

Software Enginner | 2020-2022

Developing of a VR/AR software using Aframe, WebXR and Three is.



Research Centre for Biomedical Engineering

Software Enginner | 2019-2020

Development of a Serious Game for Android for medical purposes.

ABINITIO

Abinitio

Software Enginner | 2017-2019

Worked as an intern and subsequently as a software engineer. Developed internal applications and managed databases.